# **Prashil Lonakar**

prashil.lonakar@gmail.com | +91 7558615669 | LinkedIn | Nagpur, Maharashtra

## **SUMMARY**

Software Developer Engineer with 5 years of experience in designing, developing, building, unit-testing, optimizing effective web applications and Project Managements. Possesses expertise in efficient development processes by creating user-friendly, responsive UI and minimizing bug count by 40% within the last quarter.

## **SKILLS**

Technical Skills: Angular, React, Node, Express, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, MySQL, AWS

Management & Bug tracking tools: JIRA, ClickUp, Bugzilla

Design Tools: Figma

API testing Tools: Swagger and Postman

Analytical & Product Tools: Git, Bitbucket, Google Analytics, Microsoft Excel

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Orangebits Software Technology, Nagpur

june 2019 - Present

**Senior Software Engineer** 

june 2023 - Present

Project: Rushividyabhyasam (E-learning)

Skill: React 17

- Successfully led the development process, meeting strict deadlines as well as
- Redesigned and Enhanced code quality in the application to improve UI and its functionality.

## **Project: Erp Solution**

#### Skill: Node, Express, MySQL, React 18, Redux

- Led teams with 3 developers in enhancing product functionality and building UI and API services for Erp.
- Partnered with the UX team to update a new UI for a key product, resulting in a 20% increase in user satisfaction and Improved the codebase, which increased overall application speed by 30%.

## Project: Humanest (Social-media)

## Skill: Angular 15

- Implement, design and launch the product within 6 months.
- Implemented strict security protocols for GDPR and HIPAA compliance and Attained AA conformance in accessibility standards, enhancing user experience and usability by 40%.
- Improved performance of reads to serve a large number of live users and ensure a seamless user experience across
  different interfaces.

## Software Engineer jan 2021 - june 2023

# **Project: Tree Census(Government)**

#### Skill: React 17, Redux

- Design UI of the application using materialUi. Added lazy loading which increases loading speed.
- Delivering the UI changes to meet the client deadlines.

## Project: Flipkart Health+ (Flipkart)

## Skill: Angular 6, Angular 8

 Innovated and built a sustainable code base as well as efficient services consumable, resulting in an overall reduction of original code volume. Initiate Ultra SDK to introduce micro-frontend capabilities to increase user-friendly experience.

### Project: PKI Signal to SDC (Pfizer)

## Skill: Angular 13, React

- Build a sustainable and scalable code base, resulting in handling elastic search with 10 million records at a time efficiently.
- Work together with offshore software developers, understand client needs and develop the app accordingly. which increases the user satisfaction by 50%.

#### Project: PlayFunction(E-commerce)

## Skill: Angular 8

- Redesigned components for the main webpage, which led to a 30% loading speed.
- Fixed the previous bugs and deployed the changes within the given timeline.

## **Project: HOSPITAL (Management)**

## Skill: Angular 8, NgRx, MongoDB.

- Collaborated with clients to understand their needs and create software solutions.
- Execute Angular Localization to support multi-languages in the application.

#### Project: Resimpli

#### Skill: Angular 4, Angular 10, Angular 11, Express.js, Node.js, MongoDB

- Introduce google maps and street-view in app, which result in increase of user engagement .
- Leveraged user feedback and data analytics to continuously iterate on the platform's design and functionality, improving the overall user experience.

# **Junior Software Engineer**

june 2019 - dec 2020

### Project: RECL INDIA

## Skill: Angular 8, Node. Express, MySQL

- Developed user-friendly interfaces for this software application.
- Participated with cross-functional teams to understand customer needs and develop software accordingly.

# **Project: Sigma(Fleet Management)**

## Skill: Angular 9, Angular 11, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB

• Oversaw UI and API development for Sigma. Develop the common reusability filter list component which results in a reduction of code and efficiency of the application.

## Project: Daman Online Services(Daman & Diu State Gov.)

#### Skill: Angular 4, Angular 7, Node, Express.js, MYSQL

Upgrade the Angular version 4 to 7. Improve the code quality, which reduced code and increase web loading page speed.

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Spot Award Orangebits
- Integrated Team Award Orangebits

# **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Engineering**

July 2012 - April 2017

PBCOE, Nagpur

# **LANGUAGES**

English, Hindi, Marathi